bookmarkcontent.com 2018-07-14

# Privacy Policy | Bookmark Content

This privacy policy sets out how Bookmark Content and Communications (“we” or “us”), a Spafax Group company, part of the WPP network, uses and protects any information that you give us when you use this website.

We are committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this website, then you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

### What information do we collect?

At times we may request that you voluntarily supply us with personal information through either this website, by emailing us directly or via the telephone. Generally, this information is requested when you want us to provide you with information.

We may collect the following information:

–  Name  
–  Email address  
–  Telephone number  
–  IP address (a unique identifier for your computer or other device)  
–  Mobile device ID

### How we do we use information you give us?

We will use your personal information in the following ways. In Europe, we are also required by law to state a “legal basis for processing”, i.e. to tell you on what grounds we are allowed to use your information, and this is also set out below:

We will contact you directly to request consent before processing your personal information for any other purpose than outlined in this policy.

### Do we share your information with third parties?

The personal information you provide may be shared in the following circumstances.

–  We may send your personal information to other group companies, affiliates and third parties to help us process your personal information for the purposes set out in this policy. They only have access to the personal information they need to perform those services. They are required to keep your personal information confidential and may not use it other than as we ask them to and always in accordance with this privacy policy.

–  We may send your personal information to other companies inside the WPP group if we deem them appropriate to respond to your request. Further details of our group companies can be found [here](https://www.wpp.com/wpp/companies/?PageIndex=0&SortBy=Name&PageSize%5B15%5D=15&SortReverse%5Bfalse%5D=A-Z&Mode=company).

–  We may disclose personal information to third parties when we reasonably believe we are required by law, and in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding suspected or actual unlawful or otherwise prohibited activities, including, but not limited to, fraud.

–  We may disclose your personal information if we or any of our assets are the subject of a sale or similar corporate transaction. We will ensure that the third parties who receive your personal information are required to keep it confidential.

Please be assured that, other than as set out here, we will not pass your personal data to a third-party company for any secondary or unrelated purposes without your prior consent.

### How is your information secured?

We take appropriate measures to ensure that your personal information disclosed to us is kept secure, accurate and up to date and kept only for so long as is necessary for the purposes for which it is used.

### How long do we keep your information?

We will keep your information for a reasonable period of time for the purpose for which it has been collected or as required by law.

### Controlling your personal information

You can control how your personal information is processed in the following ways.

–  **Stop further communication and withdraw consent:** if you have previously submitted your personal information via the website or other means, you may request this data is not used for further contact from us using the details in the ‘Contact Us’ section of this policy.

–  **Correct information already held:** if you believe that any information we are holding on you is incorrect or incomplete, please contact us using the details in the ‘Contact Us’ section of this policy. We will promptly correct any information found to be incorrect.

–  **Access to your data:** You have the right to ask for a copy of the personal information which we hold about you. This is referred to as a Subject Access Request. To submit a request please contact us using the details in the ‘Contact Us’ section of this policy

–  **Have your data deleted or erased:** you have the right to ask us to delete any personal data we hold about you, please contact us using the details in the ‘Contact Us’ section of this policy

### Transferring data

We are a global company and therefore we may transfer your personal information to countries around the world. We will, where the country to which your data is transferred has not been found to provide an adequate level of protection, put in place appropriate safeguards (we use standard contractual clauses) to ensure your information is protected.

### Links to other websites

Our website links to third party sites which we do not operate or endorse. These websites may use cookies and collect your personal information in accordance with their own privacy policies. This privacy policy does not apply to third party websites and we are not responsible for third party websites.

### Under 13 year olds

This website is not intended or designed to attract children under the age of 13. We do not knowingly collect personal information from or about any person under the age of 13. If you are under 13 years old and wish to ask a question or use this site in any way which requires you to submit your personal information, please ask your parent or guardian to do so on your behalf.

### Non-personal information

We may collect certain information using Crazy Egg, HubSpot, Klipfolio, Google Analytics and other tools in order for us to understand how people use our website. However, this non-personal information does not identify you. This information is used to better understand the needs of our website users in general. Bookmark may also use this information to keep track of website visits, url clicks and what pages are being viewed.

### Right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority

If you have a complaint or an issue with how we have collected or are processing your personal information you have a right to contact your Supervisory Authority. In the UK this would be the ICO and their contact details can be found [here](https://ico.org.uk/concerns/handling/).

### Regulations specific to Canada

This Policy is designed to be in compliance with Canada’s personal information Protection and Electronic Documents Act (“PIPEDA”, S.C. 2000, c. 5), Quebec’s An Act Respecting the Protection of Personal Information in the Private Sector (R.S.Q. c. P-39.1) and other provincial regulations that are deemed to be substantially similar to PIPEDA, and the Canadian law known as Canada’s Anti-Spam Law (“CASL”, S.C. 2010, c. 23). If you have any questions about our policies or if we have contacted you in error, please see the “Contact us” section below.

### Contact us

If you wish to exercise any of your rights in relation to your personal information or if you have any queries about how we use your personal information, please let us know by contacting us at the following addresses:

In EMEA and Asia:  
Bookmark Content and Communications, The Griffin Building, 83 Clerkenwell Road, London, EC1R 5AR, UK.  
Tel.:[+44 (0) 20 7734 2303](tel:+44 \(0\) 20 7734 2303)

In the Americas:  
Bookmark Content and Communications, 2 Bloor Street E, Suite 1020, Toronto, Ontario, M4W 1A8, Canada.  
Tel.: [1.888.350.2425](tel:1.888.350.2425)

Or by email: [privacy@bookmarkcontent.com.](mailto:privacy@bookmarkcontent.com)

### Changes to this policy

We review this privacy policy on a regular basis to ensure that it is up-to-date with our use of your personal information, and compliant with applicable data protection laws.

We reserve the right, at our discretion, to revise this privacy policy at any time. The updated privacy policy will be posted on our website. You are encouraged to review this privacy policy from time to time.

The current version of this policy is effective from 23rd May 2018.

### The internet and risks

Total security cannot be guaranteed on the internet, no matter how rigorous the rules or our efforts to keep all information safe. Therefore, understand and accept that Bookmark cannot be held liable for damages resulting from you submitting confidential information or personal information via the internet. These communications are at your own risk. In addition, Bookmark, its affiliates and subsidiaries, or their respective officers, affiliates, agents, partners, directors, employees, principals, licensors, representatives, successors and assigns, cannot be held liable for any losses or damages (monetary or otherwise) resulting from the misuse of any information collected by any third party or any misuse of any information collected through the website not in violation of our Policy.

## Cookie Policy

By using our website, you are agreeing to our use of cookies as described in this notice.

### What are cookies?

We may use information obtained from cookies or similar technology. Cookies are text files containing small amounts of information, which we download onto your computer or device when you visit our website. Therefore, when we refer to “you” in this section, we mean your computer. We can recognize these cookies on subsequent visits and they allow us to remember you.

Cookies come in many forms. We have set out the main types and categories of cookies that are used below. This section refers to all types and categories of cookies and not just those we use on our website.

**First and third-party cookies** – whether a cookie is first-party or third-party refers to the domain placing the cookie. First-party cookies are those set by a website that is being visited by the user, the website displayed in the URL window. Third-party cookies are cookies that are set by a domain other than that of the website being visited by the user. If a user visits a website and another entity sets a cookie through that website, this would be a third-party cookie.

**Persistent cookies** – these cookies remain on a user’s device for the period of time specified in the cookie. They are activated each time that the user visits the website that created that particular cookie.

**Session cookie** – these cookies allow website operators to link the actions of a user during a browser session. A browser session starts when a user opens the browser window and finishes when they close the browser window. Session cookies are created temporarily. Once you close the browser, all session cookies are deleted.

### What do we use cookies for?

Cookies fall into one or more of the categories set out below.

**1\. Strictly necessary cookies – these cookies enable services you have specifically asked for.**

These cookies are essential in order to enable you to move around the website and use its features, such as accessing secure areas of the website. Without these cookies, certain services you have asked for cannot be provided.

This website uses cookies in this category.

**2\. Performance cookies – these cookies collect information on the pages visited.**

These cookies collect information about how users use a website. For instance, which pages users go to most often, and if they get error messages from web pages. These cookies don’t collect information that identifies a visitor. All information these cookies collect is aggregated and therefore anonymous. They are only used to improve how the website works.

This website uses cookies in this category.

**3\. Functionality cookies – these cookies remember choices you make to improve your experience.**

These cookies allow the website to remember choices you make and provide enhanced, more personal features. They may also be used to help provide services you have asked for, such as watching a video or commenting on a blog. The information these cookies collect may be anonymized, and they cannot track your browsing activity to other websites.

This website uses cookies in this category.

**4\. Targeting cookies or advertising cookies – these cookies collect information about your browsing habits in order to make advertising relevant to you and your interests.**

These cookies are used to deliver advertisements more relevant to you and your interests. They are also used to limit the number of times you see an advertisement, as well as help measure the effectiveness of the advertising campaign. They are usually placed by advertising networks with the website operator’s permission. They remember that you have visited a website, and this information is shared with other organizations, such as advertisers. Quite often, targeting or advertising cookies will be linked to site functionality provided by the other organization.

This website doesn’t use cookies in this category.

### What cookies do we use?

**Performance/analytics/tracking:** this type of cookie provides aggregated information about where a user may go on the website.

• Google Analytics. Bookmark Content and Communications uses Google Analytics to help us analyse how visitors use the website. Among other things, Google Analytics uses cookies to collect information about the number of visits to the website, the webpage that referred visitors to the website, language, device, browser and operating system, the pages visitors view within the website and other similar details. We do not share this information with third parties. When used this way the Google Analytics cookie is a persistent cookie, and will remain on your device until the cookie expires or you delete it. These cookies may appear as _utma, _utmb, _utmc, _utmz, _utmv, _utmt.

• We also use Google Analytics as a session cookie. This cookie may appear as has_js. We do not retain this data as it is deleted upon closing of your browser, and therefore we cannot share it with any third parties.

**Social media/sharing:** these are cookies that help with the website’s functionality. These are third party cookies, and they allow you to share comments, pages, bookmarks, and likes, and help to provide access to social networking tools easily.

  * Social media widgets used on this website include LinkedIn, Twitter, and YouTube. These social media widgets collect information about your visit to the website and your use of the social platform services (for example, buttons or likes) on the website. We do not share information with these social platforms, however please keep in mind the social networks collect the data of your site visit and interaction with the social widget directly.

### Removing cookies

If you want to delete any cookies that may already be on your computer or device, please refer to the instructions for your file management software to locate the file or directory that stores cookies. If you want to stop cookies from being stored on your computer in the future, please refer to your browser manufacturer’s instructions by clicking “Help” in your browser menu. Further information on cookies is available at allaboutcookies.org. By deleting our cookies or disabling future cookies, you may not be able to access certain areas or features of our website.
